♪♪
Hi, Daddy. You're still up.
Problems in Tokyo.
Say good night, Kelly.
- Now wait just a minute.
- It's okay, Jeff.
Just go.
I'll call you in the morning.
I thought we agreed you
were through with that loser.
He's not a loser.
All right, he's a
money-grubbing snake.
Stop it.
He loves me.
Love. Love?
He loves the fact that
your last name is Blake.
Now, I don't want
you to see him again.
He just asked me to
marry him, and I said yes.
But I absolutely
forbid it, do you hear?
Kelly, come back here. Kelly!
Okay, $25 NASA.
$10 greenies and birdies.
Why don't I just give you
my car? It will be cheaper.
Hey, I don't want to rush you guys,
but I've got to be out of here by 5, okay?
Taking Granny to
the theater again?
What some people will
do to inherit a bundle.
Yeah, Stan here earned his
money the hard way... he married it.
It's tough living off royalties from
books on the crisis in American ethics.
Who knows? Maybe somebody
will make a musical out of it.
All right, who's up?
I believe you are, Mr. Blake.
Stay away from my daughter.
I love Kelly, and she loves me.
Don't give me that.
How much do you want?
You think you can buy me off?
You're not allergic to money.
How does 10 grand sound?
- Why, you dirty...
- Calm down, Jeff.
Ellis, I think we'd
better get another caddy.
Uh-huh.
Think it over, Holden.
♪♪
Come on in.
Thank God.
Go next door and
tell him to turn it down.
Why is it always me?
Why don't you go?
Fine.
We'll both go.
Mr. Holden?
For the umpteenth
time, I didn't kill anybody.
I was driving back from a
golf tournament in Columbus,
and I sure as hell didn't
shoot anybody tonight.
That's all I'm going to say
until my lawyer gets here.
Well, speak of the devil.
What the hell took you so long?
It's the middle
of the night, Ellis.
Ben, I'd like you to
meet Lauren Richmond.
She's our new deputy D.A.
She'll be handling this case.
Lauren, Ben Matlock.
Mr. Matlock, I can't tell
you what an honor this is.
I've always thought that your
defense in The People vs. Baker
was one of the most brilliantly
constructed and argued pieces of its time.
People vs. Baker was 25
years ago, before you were born.
I've read every
case you ever tried.
I did my junior thesis on you.
Hey, hey, what is
this? Happy hour?
Cut the crapola and
get me out of here.
Could I speak with
my client by myself?
Call me in my office.
What's up?
They think I killed this sleazy
little dirtbag named Jeffrey Holden.
Tell me about this
sleazy little dirtbag.
He was a caddy
at the country club.
A couple of months ago, he
started dating my daughter,
but he was just after her money.
The day before yesterday,
I offered him some.
I told him I'd give him $10,000 if
he'd break it off with my daughter.
Did he take it?
No.
No, no, he was
holding out for more.
I can spot a
golddigger a mile away.
Believe me, I wasn't
married twice for nothing.
Well, anyway, the dirty little creep
got himself murdered last night,
and whoever did it used my gun.
Oh, you own a gun?
This is America. Of
course I own a gun.
I got a .22 in my
glove compartment.
I guess they went
over it, did they?
Yeah, they're pretty sure
that's the murder weapon.
I kept trying to tell them that
somebody could have stolen it,
but they keep coming
back to the money.
What money?
Jeff Holden had a bunch of
money on him when he was found.
$10,000?
It's a setup, Ben.
I swear to you I have never been
anywhere near Jeff Holden's place.
Ben!
Well, where were you last night?
I was driving back
from Columbus.
I'd been playing golf there all
day at Briarcrest Country Club.
They have this tournament
there every year, an invitational.
I don't suppose
you stopped for gas
or helped a pretty young
girl whose car had stalled
or there's somebody
we could call?
I came straight home.
I left at 6, and I get
in my house at 8:00.
Nobody saw you?
Not that I know of.
Why does it always
have to be that way?
Ben, if I was going to kill this
guy... This Jeffrey Holden...
Would I shoot him
with my own gun
and then put it in my
own glove compartment?
I'd have to be an idiot.
I'm one of the wealthiest
men in the world.
Do you think I got that
rich by being stupid?
You never know.
I can't believe it.
I'm going up
against Ben Matlock.
I know what you mean...
Butterflies the size of basketball.
Julie, you're just trying
to make me feel better.
A distinguished lawyer like you
doesn't get nervous, but I'm a nobody.
You'll be just fine.
Besides, it's just
a bail hearing.
The only tricky part about a
bail hearing is staying awake.
You'll be great.
Thanks.
All right. Let's get started.
Your motion, Miss Richmond?
If it please the court, the state
asks that bail be set at $2 million.
Two million dollars?
Sir, only your attorney has the
right to speak, and it's not yet his turn.
Please be quiet.
The defendant is a
man of immense wealth
with far-flung business interests and
access to a virtually limitless capital.
In the state's view, $2 million is
very reasonable and eminently fair.
- You've got to be out of your mind.
- Ellis...
- That's enough.
- Ellis, don't.
She makes it sound like all I've got
to do is walk up to a cash machine
and $2 million will fall out.
Mr. Matlock,
control your client.
Your Honor, may I have a moment to instruct
my client as to proper courtroom decorum?
By all means.
Shut up and sit down!
Thank you, Your Honor.
I'll entertain your
motion now, Mr. Matlock.
If it please the court, my
client is a wealthy man, yes,
but he's also very much
a pillar of the community.
His business is here. His
family is here. His friends.
There's virtually no
risk of flight whatsoever.
Bail should be set at...
$200,000 at the absolute most.
Your Honor, the state
would like to point out
that in this day of computers and fax
machines and satellite communications,
Mr. Blake could run his
empire from anywhere.
The risk of flight
here is enormous.
Your Honor...
The court's motion granted.
Bail is set at $2 million.
You're as crazy as she is.
Excuse me?
I didn't kill that bum.
Why would I run away?
Give me one good reason.
Your client's not
listening to you, counselor.
Get me out of here.
I have work to do.
Maybe he just needs a
little time to compose himself.
Twenty-four hours in
jail for contempt of court.
Okay, sir, let me have your
watch, and let's empty your pockets.
Okay, watch.
Money clip.
Wallet.
What are these things?
- Ball markers.
- What?
- Okay, ball markers.
Keys and change.
Anything else, sir?
Ahh.
Hi. Fred Bigelow.
Just got here myself.
What do you want? The
top bunk or the bottom?
Okay, Sergeant.
Hi, Bob.
Hey, Conrad.
Where's Ben?
He's busy.
Is that the new assistant
D.A. Ben was talking about?
That's Lauren Richmond.
- I hear she's good.
- Mm-hmm.
So find anything interesting?
Nothing that doesn't
fit the prevailing theory.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Ellis Blake walked in here
and tried to pay Jeff Holden off.
Jeff Holden either
refused or wanted more.
Blake then pulled a
gun and killed him.
And left all this money behind?
Jeff Holden must have dropped
it when he took the bullet.
It was all over the place.
Mr. Blake just didn't
have time to pick it up.
This guy was a caddy?
I bet there are golf pros
that don't live this well.
Lieutenant, I found this on the
ground just outside the back door.
It's a ball marker.
Golfers use them when their ball
is in the line of someone else's putt.
Briarcrest Invitational,
dated yesterday.
That's the tournament
Ellis Blake said he played in.
I'm telling you it isn't mine.
But you had ball markers
in your pocket the other day.
Everybody else who was
at that tournament did, too.
Hell, they were even
selling them for souvenirs.
I wasn't there, Ben...
Not that night or any night.
You act like you think I did it.
You're kidding.
Jeff Holden was a blackmailer?
Well, I checked his bank,
and he had been making large
cash deposits for almost a year.
Maybe he was pushing.
Maybe.
Would you mind?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Then I checked with your bank,
and you had been making large
cash withdrawals for almost a year.
Why would you
check with my bank?
Well, I figure if somebody
was framing Ellis
that it had to be
somebody who knew
that Ellis had offered
$10,000 to Jeff Holden.
Ooh, boy, that was a nice shot.
Actually, I hit it fat.
Yeah?
What did...
Jeff Holden have on you?
If you don't tell me now,
I'll ask you in open court.
He had somehow found out
that the restaurant I'm
trying to sell in San Francisco
isn't exactly the financial
bonanza my books would indicate.
Jeff said he could prove that.
Since I was in no position
to call his bluff, I paid him.
Well, do you have any idea
where you were that night?
At my restaurant, cooking.
He had a tape of a
conversation that he and I had.
Oh, you hit too far under it.
What was in the conversation?
It was about my grandmother.
Oh, oh.
The one who controls
all the money in the family.
- I love my grandmother, Mr. Matlock.
- Yeah?
Well, now you near
about hit it too high.
Look here, how
about... Look here.
No, look here. Now look. Look.
Try to hit it just under
the square, right?
Just under the square and just
knock the fire out of that sucker.
It'll go flying out of there.
See there.
Well, these things
are hard to get out of.
So you love your grandmother?
Yeah. It's just that she's
old and she's had a long life
and now her health is failing,
so maybe it's just as well.
So it's time to
go to her reward.
I said that to Jeff Holden once,
and he said he could arrange it.
Well, naturally I said
I wasn't interested,
but then later on I found out he
not only taped the conversation,
he edited it together to make it
sound like I asked him to knock her off.
Oh, and then he'd play
it to your grandmother.
Oh.
The happiest moment of my life was
when I found out he was murdered.
Oh. Where were you that night?
Having dinner with
my grandmother.
It takes a lot of work to
inherit some money, doesn't it?
Yeah, well, what
do you suggest now?
Oh, I don't know. I don't
know anything about golf.
Jeff Holden blackmailing me?
That's ridiculous.
Then all the money you're taking
out of the bank and giving to him
I guess is just a big tip, huh?
What I do with my money
is my business, Mr. Matlock.
You mean your wife's
money, don't you?
Excuse me.
Your wife would cut you off at your
knees if she knew, wouldn't she?
Knew what?
About your affair with
Tom Neville's wife.
Yeah, she'd cut off all your
money, she'd ruin your career.
I mean, who wants to read books on
ethics by your garden-variety adulterer?
What makes you think
I'm seeing Tom's wife?
Ellis told me.
Things like this don't
stay secret too long.
Jeff Holden had pictures.
He said that he'd show them to
Tom unless I gave him money.
But I didn't kill
him. I couldn't have.
Why?
Because I was with
Caroline Neville that night.
This boy is blackmailing you, and
you're paying him to carry your clubs?
You people are nuts.
Now, look out
about that little ball.
- Strike there. Right here. See?
- Thanks.
Just right there. Watch.
Here's your witness list.
Lauren was supposed
to send that to my office.
- She just forgot.
- Oh.
Lauren reminds me of me when I
started my first case against you.
I was so overwhelmed and
determined and enthused and scared.
Scared of what?
Of you.
You are what scared me.
Things are a little
different now, aren't they?
Lauren says she finds
you very intimidating.
She sure didn't act
it in the courtroom.
She went right for my throat
and got what she wanted, too.
Beginner's luck.
I just held my breath,
dove in, and prayed.
I'm surprised you didn't
hear my knees knocking.
I was listening to my own.
You? Never.
I see Julie gave
you the witness list.
It turns out there's one more
person to add. He just came forward.
- Rob Barton.
- Who's that?
He lives across the street
from Jeffrey Holden's.
He claims to have seen your
client at Holden's townhouse
the night he was murdered.
Okay, I lied. I'm sorry.
What's wrong with you, Ellis?
Why didn't you tell me you went
to Jeff Holden's house that night?
And give her more ammunition?
Besides, I didn't
think anybody saw me.
Ellis, you can't
lie to me like that.
I didn't kill him, damn it. I
went there to talk to him.
I didn't even get up to the front door
before I turned around to go home.
I never went inside.
All rise.
Be seated.
Miss Richmond, you
may call your next witness.
The state calls Lieutenant
Bob Brooks to the stand.
Do you recognize
this gun, Lieutenant?
Yes, I do. It has my tag.
That gun is registered
to Ellis Blake
and was found in the glove
compartment of his car.
The bullet that killed Jeff
Holden came from this gun?
Yes, ma'am, it did.
Could you identify this for us?
Yes. It's a ball marker
from a golf tournament.
It was found on the ground
outside the decedent's town home
about 4 feet from the back
door on the day after the murder.
Have you come across any others like it
in the course of this murder investigation?
Yes. We found three just
like it in Mr. Blake's possession
at the time of his arrest.
Thank you.
Mr. Matlock?
No questions, Your Honor.
The witness may step down.
Why didn't you ask him anything?
Because the more he
talks, the guiltier you get.
Your Honor, may we approach?
Your Honor, I just learned that someone
with information relevant to this case
has come forward
and is ready to testify.
- I'd like to put him on the stand.
- Your Honor...
Oh, I'm sorry to do this to Mr. Matlock,
and he has every right to object,
but the witness is out
in the hall right now,
and I don't know how
long he'll be available.
But, Your Honor...
If you would allow me to
call him now, Your Honor,
I would have no
problem whatsoever
with your then calling a
recess until tomorrow morning,
thereby giving Mr. Matlock
ample time to prepare his cross.
Counselor?
- Well, I guess I can live with that.
- Mm-hmm.
The state calls Mr. Fred
Bigelow to the stand.
That's the guy I was in
jail with. What's going on?
My name is Fred Bigelow, and right
now I'm living at the Downtown Hotel.
Mr. Bigelow, I understand you
know the defendant Mr. Blake.
That's right. He and I shared
accommodations recently.
You were in a jail cell
together, is that what you mean?
Yeah.
You met the defendant
on the 24th of last month,
the day after Jeff Holden's
murder. Is that right?
Yes, that's when we
became cellmates.
Mr. Bigelow, have you
been promised anything
by anyone in the
District Attorney's office
in exchange for your
testimony here today?
No, ma'am.
I'm here because I decided it was
my duty as a citizen of this fair city
to come forward
with what I know.
And that is?
Well, we got to
talking in that jail cell,
and being that he'd
never been in jail before,
he asked me for some advice.
What kind of advice?
Well, stuff like "Do you
keep your mouth shut
or do you tell your
lawyer you did it?"
Of course, me, I told him, "Hey,
you don't admit nothing to nobody,
especially if you're guilty."
- You liar! I never said that!
- Ellis, sit down!
I never said a word to you
the whole time I was there!
- Quiet!
- Who bribed you?
I demand order!
Who paid you off?
Answer me, you slimy little rat!
I think somebody paid that Bigelow
fellow to get up on the stand and lie.
If the bailiff
hadn't been there,
Ellis would have punched
Fred Bigelow's lights right out.
Ha ha! I'd kind of
like to have seen that.
Are you positive Fred
Bigelow wasn't telling the truth?
Guys like Ellis don't kill
people, they buy them.
And I don't think
Ellis bought anybody.
Did you talk to Miles
Turner's grandmother?
She confirmed his alibi.
Says he came to
her house around 7
and, in her words, spent the next
three hours with her at the theater,
fawning and groveling
like a sniveling toad.
What about the other two?
I'm on my way to Tom
Neville's restaurant right now.
How about dropping a
toothbrush off for Ellis on your way?
Sure. Where is he at?
In jail. Contempt, you know.
What's that you're
cooking there?
Sautéed duck liver with Porcini
mushrooms and a little brandy.
You could pour a quart of
brandy on it. Liver is still liver to me.
What else have you got?
Do you mind? I'm a
little too busy to chat.
- I hear the food here is great.
- It is.
Do you like working here?
I own this restaurant.
You do? What do you make best?
Look, I'm not even
going to cook here tonight.
Ann.
Darn, that's bad luck.
Well, when are you here?
Every night but Wednesday.
Look, you ought to
tell me where you work
so I can come down and
talk to you when you're busy.
I'd like that. Morgan's
Mortuary on Peachtree.
I should have known.
Hi. My name is Tom,
and I'm an alcoholic.
Hi, Tom.
Are you still here?
Yeah. Do you have a minute?
Sure? What's the problem?
So far, so good.
I just wanted to tell you how much your
advice and your support have meant to me.
Oh, that's sweet, but I
haven't done anything special.
Oh, of course you have.
Isn't there something
I can do for you?
Well, as a matter
of fact, there is.
You just go into that courtroom and
do the best you can and win this case.
That will be plenty.
Thanks.
I'm so proud of you.
I really am.
Lieutenant Brooks, did I
call you yesterday afternoon?
Yes, you did.
What was the nature
of our conversation?
You wanted to know if the money
found in Jeff Holden's townhouse
had been analyzed
for fingerprints.
It hadn't, so I sent
it out for lab tests.
- Do you have the results of these tests?
- Yes, I do.
Would you tell the
court what they are?
The lab found the defendant's
fingerprints on three $50 bills.
- What?
- Ellis, hold it.
That's impossible! I never saw
that money, let alone touch it.
Mr. Blake, sit
down and be quiet!
What the hell is
going on around here?
Your Honor, could I have a
moment with my client in private?
You do that, Mr. Matlock,
because one more outburst like that,
you'll both be
spending the night in jail.
Court will recess
for 15 minutes.
I don't believe this.
I'm still being set up.
When is it going to stop?
And when are you going to
start doing something about it?
There's nothing I can do, Ellis.
What the hell kind
of an answer is that?
You don't believe me anymore.
It doesn't matter what I believe.
The jury doesn't believe you.
The evidence is stacked
against you... I'm talking stacked.
You want me to plead guilty?
No.
I want to see if I can
cut a deal for you.
If this thing goes before
the jury, we're going to lose.
No!
You've got to face facts.
The fact is I didn't
do it. I'm innocent.
Now put me on the stand.
No, that's a bad idea.
I'm going on the stand
whether you like it or not.
I don't like it. No.
You'll hang yourself.
I don't give a damn!
I'm going on the stand.
You're my lawyer,
put me on the stand.
Mr. Blake, did you go see Jeff
Holden on the 23rd of last month?
Yes, I did. I drove
to his townhouse.
I wanted to talk to him about
his relationship with my daughter.
- Did you speak with him?
- No. I never went inside.
I turned around before I
even got to his front door.
Did you... kill Jeff Holden?
No, I did not.
This is your gun, isn't it?
Yes. I kept it in the glove
compartment of my car.
Do you always
remember to lock your car?
No. In fact, I rarely remember.
So someone could have stolen
this gun from your glove compartment,
used it to kill Jeff Holden,
and then put it back in your car?
Easily.
Thank you, Mr. Blake.
Miss Richmond?
Thank you, Your Honor.
I'm sorry, Mr. Blake,
if I sound confused,
but didn't you originally tell the
police that on the night of the murder
you were in your car, driving
home from a golf tournament?
No.
- So you lied before?
- Well... Yes or no?
Did you or did you not lie to the police
regarding your whereabouts that night?
Yes. But I never
went inside. I...
Oh, yes, you went inside.
You went inside to deliver
the $10,000 you'd promised him
if he left your daughter
alone. Didn't you?
No, I didn't.
Then how did your fingerprints
get on that money, Mr. Blake?
I don't know.
Didn't you give the money to Jeff
Holden, argue with him, then shoot him?
No!
Then how did a bullet from your
gun wind up in his heart, Mr. Blake?
I don't know. Somebody stole...
And after you shot him,
you ran out the back door,
and maybe you reached into
your pocket for your car keys,
and in the process,
one of the ball markers
that were in your
pocket fell to the ground.
I didn't shoot him, though
God knows I felt like it.
And I didn't run out the back door
because I never got to the front door.
And I didn't leave a ball
marker on the ground!
I had three of them,
and I've still got three.
- Maybe you replaced it, huh, Mr. Blake?
- No!
That was your marker outside
the back door, wasn't it, Mr. Blake?
I was set up, damn it.
The money. The gun. The marker.
Somebody used it to set me up.
I didn't do it!
You were spotted at
the scene of the crime.
Your gun did the killing.
Your money... Your
fingerprints were on it.
Your ball marker at
the foot of the steps.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm afraid this man is
fighting a losing battle.
Thank you, Your Honor.
We find the defendant,
Ellis Blake, guilty.
Thank you, ladies and
gentlemen of the jury.
You are dismissed, and the
defendant is remanded to custody.
Sentencing will be in this
court on the 17th of next month.
Court is now in recess.
We've got to appeal.
Okay.
I'm innocent. I didn't kill him.
You've got to do something.
Well, don't just stand
there! Do something!
I'm sorry, Ellis. I truly am.
Higher. Higher over there.
- Perfect. Perfect.
- Right there?
Thank you.
- Cheers.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Hi.
It's all clear.
- Hi.
I'm looking for Lauren Richmond.
She's not here right now.
Can I help you with something?
No. It's personal.
She's due back in a half
hour. You're welcome to wait.
We're throwing a
little party for her.
Could you just tell her that
Peter Vanderhoff is in town?
Sure.
How do you spell that?
V-A-N-D-E-R-H-O-F-F.
- And you know her?
- Yeah.
We had a drink down
in Columbus last week.
Just tell her I'll try
to catch her later.
Thanks.
Ben? Hi.
Listen, if you're not busy,
I wondered if you could take
a drive with me to Columbus.
The Briarcrest Country Club.
Therefore, Your Honor,
the defense moves
that the guilty verdict
against Ellis Blake be set aside
on the basis of
prosecutorial misconduct.
This is an outrage.
There was no misconduct
on the part of the prosecution.
Well, Mr. Matlock seems to
feel he can prove there was.
He's wasting the court's time, to
say nothing of impugning my integrity.
If I may be blunt, Your Honor,
this merely demonstrates
that Mr. Matlock is nothing
more than a sore loser.
Well, this is unusual,
I'll grant you that.
But I'm willing to allow him
some leeway in this matter.
But, Your Honor...
At his request, I've compelled all
the original witnesses to appear.
Now, Mr. Matlock, you have
one hour of the court's time,
but mind you, if I detect so
much as a whiff of sour grapes,
it may be the last hour you'll
spend in court for a long time.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
The defense calls
Mr. Dennis Frye to the stand.
Do you swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the
truth, so help you God?
I do.
- State your name, please.
- Dennis Frye.
- Be seated.
- Thank you.
Mr. Frye, would you please tell
the court what you do for a living?
I manage the pro shop at
the Briarcrest Country Club.
That's where they held their
invitational golf tournament last month.
Yes, it is.
Now, tell me, Mr. Frye,
uh, have you ever seen this
young lady down there before?
Yes, I have.
I never forget a customer.
She came into your shop?
Mm-hmm. During the tournament.
Didn't buy much, though.
Do you remember what she bought?
A souvenir ball marker.
One ball marker?
That's it?
Well, it struck me as kind of strange,
too. That's why it stuck in my mind.
Did the date she bought
it stick in your mind?
Mm-hmm. The last day of
the tournament... the 24th.
Your Honor, I submit
that Miss Richmond knew
that my client had three souvenir
golf ball markers in his pocket
when he was arrested
for contempt of court,
and the marker she bought and
planted outside Jeff Holden's apartment
was put there to further
implicate my client in his murder.
That is an extremely
serious allegation.
Miss Richmond?
I absolutely deny
this, Your Honor,
and I caution Mr. Matlock that
these false statements are unethical
and may subject him to
disciplinary action by the state bar.
Mr. Matlock?
I'd like to continue,
if I may, Your Honor.
Proceed.
The defense would
like to excuse Mr. Frye.
- Thank you.
- You may step down.
And call Mr. Stanton
Avery to the stand.
Do you swear to tell
the truth, the whole truth,
and nothing but the
truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- State your name, please.
- Stanton Avery.
- Be seated.
Uh, Jeff Holden was
blackmailing you, wasn't he?
- Yes, he was.
- Why?
Because he found out that I was
seeing the wife of a friend of mine.
So you were paying him
to keep his mouth shut.
Yes.
I bet he was bleeding you dry.
Very dry.
And that's why you killed him?
I did no such thing.
I was with my friend's
wife at that time.
No, you weren't.
She was with her husband at an
Anonymous meeting that evening...
The same as every
Wednesday evening.
Your Honor, I object.
Mr. Matlock is
misleading this court.
He says he's trying to prove
prosecutorial misconduct,
but all he's really doing
is retrying his case.
I must admit I'm not entirely comfortable
with this line of questioning, Mr. Matlock.
I'm sorry, Your
Honor. I'll move on.
Would you tell the court,
please, who Karen Brown is?
I don't believe I know
any Karen Brown.
Well, sure you do.
She's the vice president at the Greater
Atlanta Bank where you do your banking.
She's the one who
helps you out, you know,
so you won't have to stand
in line like everyone else.
- Yes, yes. That Karen Brown.
- Yeah, yeah.
When I asked the police to
do a full fingerprint analysis
of all the money that was
found at the scene of the crime,
whose fingerprints do you think
they found on almost all the bills?
I have no idea.
Karen Brown's. Karen Brown's.
Because that's where
the money came from...
Not from my client's
bank, but from yours.
Her fingerprints were found
on every single bill but three...
Three 50s on which my client's
fingerprints so conveniently were found.
Why this discrepancy?
While he was in jail
for contempt of court,
somebody went through the envelope
containing my client's possessions
and removed three
50s from his money clip
and replaced them with
three 50s of her own,
then went into
the evidence room,
removed three 50s from the money
found at the scene of the crime,
replaced them with three
50s belonging to my client
so that his fingerprints
could be found on them.
Now, who did this?
Deputy D.A. Lauren
Richmond, of course.
Can you substantiate this?
Look here, Your Honor.
She signed into
booking on the 24th,
signed into the evidence
room on the 25th.
And I'm sure if we had a
heart-to-heart talk with Mr. Fred Bigelow,
we would discover that Miss Richmond
is responsible for his testimony, too.
The first thing you did
after you overheard my client
trying to buy off Jeff Holden
was go to your bank and have your
friend Karen count you out $10,000 in 50s.
Then you stole Ellis' gun
from the glove compartment
where you knew
he always kept it.
You figured he would be driving back
from the golf tournament in Columbus
and wouldn't have an alibi
so you went to Jeff Holden's
house and shot him with Ellis' gun.
Then later that night, you replaced
Ellis' gun to the glove compartment.
And Ellis helped you himself
by lying about where he
was at the time of the murder.
But Miss Richmond is wrong.
My client is not guilty.
You are.
Your Honor, I ask the
court's permission to speak.
Yes, you have it.
In view of the behavior of
my associate Miss Richmond,
I am replacing her as of
now, if it pleases the court.
It does.
Miss Richmond, as you
well know, obstruction
of justice is a
criminal offense.
You have jeopardized
your entire career.
Have you anything to say?
Your Honor, I was just so tired
of seeing guilty men go free,
and there was so much real
evidence against Ellis Blake,
I was certain he was guilty.
I know I did wrong, but I
thought it was for the right reason.
Miss Richmond, I am ordering
all the evidence against you
forwarded to the proper
authorities for further investigation.
Your Honor, the state would
like to join with the defense
in asking for a judgment
notwithstanding the verdict
and dismissal of all
charges against Ellis Blake.
So ordered.
Bailiff, take the
witness into custody.
Mr. Blake, you are hereby dismissed
with this court's profound apologies.
And we are dismissed.
That's it? It's over?
It's over.
You're innocent, and it's over.
Thank you, Ben.
I'm sorry.
Me, too.
I was just under
so much pressure
going up against the famous Ben
Matlock my first time out the gate,
I guess I just kind of lost it.
You know, flipped
out temporarily.
I mean, you could tell
them that, couldn't you?
That I didn't really know what I was
doing and that I deserve another chance?
I don't think so.
I trusted her.
I trusted her, too.
Well, I feel like a fool.
Well, I trusted her because
of what she said she was,
but she sure proved
otherwise, didn't she?
You mean innocent
until proven guilty?
Where have I heard that before?
Dag-gone if I know,
but if you'll buy me a big
supper, maybe we can talk it over.
Let's go.
www.tvsubtitles.net